RANDY R. BIANCHI

3 Springhouse Rd., Hampden, MA 01036 (413) 218-6612 • randyb7619@hotmail.com

PROFILE

Successful manager with more than 10 years' experience in consultative sales, staff supervision and training. Strengths include demonstrated ability to consistently meet or surpass sales goals, combined with effective supervision, training, presentations and marketing. In depth knowledge of energy industry and sales force management.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Project Planning and Management
- Identification and Pursuit of Growth Areas
- Building and Expansion of Client Base(s)
- Profitability Projections and Sales Reports
- Volume, Revenue and Expense Controls
- Customer Consultations, Bids and Estimates
- Customer Satisfaction and Retention
- Marketing and Product Promotion

- Educational Seminars and Presentations
- Hiring, Supervision and Performance Reviews
- Teambuilding and Work Group Management
- Staff Training and Meeting Facilitation
- Design of Compensation Plans and Contracts
- Quality Control for Production Activities
- Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND AWARDS

- Consistently achieved top sales rankings from multiple employers, including #1 in company natural gas sales (Secure Energy Solutions, LLC); 1st of 24 in regional sales;14th of 142 in area sales and 31st of 525 in national sales (Schering-Plough Pharmaceuticals.)
- Increased employers' overall territory market share by 36% within 12 months.
- Restructured sales force and modified current sales strategies to improve outcomes, resulting in a 38% average increase month over month, with over \$1M in added revenue in a10 month period.
- Received multiple awards, including: Summer Sizzler award for increasing market share; Best District
 Presentation of 10, 2 Shining Performance awards for exceeding sales goals and winning district
 challenge; Special Recognition Award for effective training of district representative and Certificate of
 Appreciation for service in the patient assistance program.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Creative Material Technologies, Ltd.

2011- Present

Independent Business Development Representative

- Implement business development and conduct sales to hardscape and concrete manufacturers.
- Maintain working knowledge of research and development projects and industry product applications.
- Oversee quality control of production processes (testing, evaluation and inspection.)
- Conduct customer consultations to assess overall effectiveness and value of products and services.

Greenpatch® by Green Product Solutions, Inc., Mt. Vernon, NY Independent Sales Consultant

2010 - 2011

- Sell finished cold-patch material to end users (municipalities) and asphalt producers.
- Motivate manufacturers and distributors to produce product regionally for end use customers.
- Oversee quality control process during plant production runs.
- Network and maintain customer industry contacts through trade shows and product demonstrations.
- Educate customers on state VOC laws (pollution) and facilitate usage shift from traditional to green materials.

Secure Energy Solutions, LLC, Springfield, MA

2007 - 2010

Director of Sales Training and Development, Promoted from Energy Specialist, (2009 - 2010)

- Directed business acquisition and developed growth plans for expansion into emerging markets.
- Created and directed new telemarketing and sales departments; developed and structured department compensation plans.
- Hired new division managers, supervised and evaluated sales team (6), conducted staff trainings on energy industry, sales process and time management.
- Created and oversaw new advertising, materials design and coordination of trade shows and public events.

Energy Specialist, (2007 - 2009)

- Appointed and acted as official Franklin-Covey® Planner Training Expert for company sales force.
- Appointed and acted as management liasion to major energy group (Energy New England.)
- Developed and presented televised advertising segment on energy (YouTube broadcast.)

RANDY R. BIANCHI, Page 2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, continued

Canterbury Café, Agawam, MA

2006 - 2007

Owner, Manager

- Oversaw all operations, including hiring, supervising and training 5 employees.
- Managed all financial and accounting functions.
- Designed all marketing materials and advertising campaigns.

Schering-Plough Pharmaceuticals, Kenilworth, NJ

2004 - 2006

Professional Sales Representative and Appointed District Allergy Product Expert

- Conducted sales to private practices (internists, allergists and ear, nose and throat specialists.)
- Researched and presented industry and product information to sales force.
- Lectured and proctored exams for Schering Pharmacy Development Program for pharmacists.

King Pharmaceuticals, Bristol, TN

2001 - 2004

Professional Sales Representative, Promoted in 2003 from Sales Representative

- Maintained responsibility for increasing overall territory market share and consistently meeting sales goals.
- Conducted sales to private practices (internists, endocrinologists and cardiologists.)
- Facilitated speaker programs to drive business and promote new drug indications.

EDUCATION

Western New England College, Springfield, MA, Bachelor of Science in Business Administration,

Major: Marketing Communications and Advertising

ADDITIONAL COURSEWORK

Springfield Technical Community College, Springfield, MA

Pre-Med Coursework: 24 Credits